Guide to the Associated Students of Central Washington University, Symposium Committee Records 1915-1984 (bulk 1962-1970)
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Associated Students of Central Washington University, Symposium Committee Records
1915-1984 (bulk 1962-1970)
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG008-07-12
Associated Students of Central Washington University
4.0 cubic feet 8 legal sized document cases Correspondence, newspaper clippings, new releases, photographs, and ephemera in good condition
This collection consists of correspondence, newspaper clippings, and ephemera related to symposia, conferences, workshops and lectures held at Central Washington State College (presently Central Washington University) from 1915 to 1984.
Historical Note
The Symposium Committee of the Associated Students of Central Washington State College was established by the request of President James Brooks during the first year of his administration in 1962. It was during his inauguration that the first symposium on American values was held on campus. The annual event reached its pinnacle in the mid 1960s but by the late 1960s interest in the program declined significantly and eventually was discontinued in 1971.
This collection consists of correspondence, newspaper clippings and ephemera related to symposiums, conferences, workshops and lectures held at Central Washington State College (presently Central Washington University) from 1915 to 1984. The bulk of the collection documents the annual Symposium on American Values which date from 1962 to 1970. The series on the Symposium on American Values contain invitations, correspondence and transcripts from internationally prominent scholars, American politicians and political activists that presented papers and partook in panel discussions. Included in the collection are newspaper clippings and ephemera related to conferences, workshops and lectures held on the Central Washington University campus from 1915 to 1984. Of note are appearances by Timothy Leary and Stokely Carmichael, and the controversy surrounding the cancelled appearance of Gus Hall.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Organized alphabetically by subject heading title. Chronological arrangement.
Open to the public for educational research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Associated Students of Central Washington University
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Symposia and seminars series; Carmichael, Stokely--Public appearances.; Leary, Timothy, 1920-1996--Public appearances
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – General, 1915 (Box-folder  1-1)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – General, 1932-1939 (Box-folder  1-2)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – General, 1941-1949 (Box-folder  1-3)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings, 1945-1946 (Box-folder  1-4)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings, 1946-1947 (Box-folder  1-5)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings, 1947-1948 (Box-folder  1-6)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings, 1948-1949 (Box-folder  1-7)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1950 (Box-folder  1-8)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1951 (Box-folder  1-9)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1952 (Box-folder  1-10)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1953 (Box-folder  1-11)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1954 (Box-folder  1-12)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1955 (Box-folder  1-13)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1956 (Box-folder  1-14)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1957 (Box-folder  1-15)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1958 (Box-folder  1-16)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1959 (Box-folder  1-17)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1960 (Box-folder  1-18)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1961 (Box-folder  1-19)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1962 (Box-folder  1-20)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1963 (Box-folder  1-21)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Newspaper clippings and ephemera, 1964 (Box-folder  1-22)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1966 (Box-folder  2-1)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1967 (Box-folder  2-2)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1968 (Box-folder  2-3)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1969 (Box-folder  2-4)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1960s (Box-folder  2-5)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1970 (Box-folder  2-6)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1971 (Box-folder  2-7)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1972 (Box-folder  2-8)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1973 (Box-folder  2-9)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1974 (Box-folder  2-10)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1975 (Box-folder  2-11)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1977 (Box-folder  2-12)
- Conferences, workshops and lectures – Ephemera, 1970s (Box-folder  2-13)
- Gus Hall Affair – Correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder  2-14)
- Gus Hall Affair – Newspaper clippings, 1962 (Box-folder  2-15)
- Gus Hall Affair – A Report by James M. Mattis, 1964 (Box-folder  2-16)
- Gus Hall Affair – Speaker policy, 1962 (Box-folder  2-17)
- Speaker policy, 1943-1966 (Box-folder  2-18)
- Speakers – Allen, Sir Richard, 1969 (Box-folder  2-19)
- Speakers – Cain, Stanley, 1969 (Box-folder  2-20)
- Speakers – Cleveland, Harlan (Box-folder  3-1)
- Speakers – Creston, Paul (Box-folder  3-2)
- Speakers – Harris, Marvin (Box-folder  3-3)
- Speakers – Savelle, Max (Box-folder  3-4)
- Summary – Annual School Leaders Conference (Box-folder  3-5)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1962-March, 1962 (Box-folder  3-6)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, April, 1962 (Box-folder  3-7)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1962 (Box-folder  3-8)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, June, 1962-December, 1962 (Box-folder  3-9)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1963-April, 1963 (Box-folder  3-10)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1963-December, 1963 (Box-folder  4-1)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1964-April, 1964 (Box-folder  4-2)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1964-December, 1964 (Box-folder  4-3)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, October, 1964-April, 1965 (Box-folder  4-4)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1965-December, 1965 (Box-folder  4-5)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1966-April, 1966 (Box-folder  4-6)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1966-December, 1966 (Box-folder  4-7)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1967-April, 1967 (Box-folder  4-8)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1967-December, 1967 (Box-folder  4-9)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1968-April, 1968 (Box-folder  5-1)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, May, 1968-December, 1968 (Box-folder  5-2)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, January, 1969-March, 1969 (Box-folder  5-3)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, April, 1969-November, 1969 (Box-folder  5-4)
- Symposium on American Values – Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder  5-5)
- Symposium on You, the University and the Future – Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box-folder  5-6)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box-folder  5-7)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box-folder  5-8)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box-folder  5-9)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box-folder  5-10)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box-folder  6-1)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box-folder  6-2)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box-folder  6-3)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder  6-4)
- Symposium on American Values – Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box-folder  6-5)
- Symposium on You, the University and the Future – Miscellaneous, 1984-1985 (Box-folder  6-6)
- Symposium on American Values – Newspaper clippings and news releases, 1962 (Box-folder  6-7)
- Symposium on American Values – Newspaper clippings and news releases, 1963 (Box-folder  6-8)
- Symposium on American Values – Newspaper clippings and news releases, 1964 (Box-folder  6-9)
- Symposium on American Values – Newspaper clippings and news releases, 1965 (Box-folder  6-10)
- Symposium on American Values – Newspaper clippings and news releases, 1967 (Box-folder  6-11)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1962 (Box-folder  6-12)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1963 (Box-folder  6-13)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1964 (Box-folder  6-14)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1965 (Box-folder  6-15)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1966 (Box-folder  6-16)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1967 (Box-folder  6-17)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1968 (Box-folder  6-18)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1968 (Box-folder  6-19)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1969 (Box-folder  6-20)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1969 (Box-folder  7-1)
- Symposium on American Values – Publicity, 1970 (Box-folder  7-2)
- Symposium on Community Days on Caring - Publicity, 1974 (Box-folder  7-3)
- Symposium on the Family: Past, Present and Future Alternatives - Publicity, 1975 (Box-folder  7-4)
- Symposium on Surplus of Quantity / Shortage of Quality – Publicity, 1975 (Box-folder  7-5)
- Symposium on You, the University and the Future – Publicity, 1985 (Box-folder  7-6)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Burke, Kenneth, 1962 (Box-folder  7-7)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Muller, Herbert, 1962 (Box-folder  7-8)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Pelikan, Jaroslav, 1962 (Box-folder  7-9)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Progoff, Ira, 1962 (Box-folder  7-10)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Taylor, Harold, 1962 (Box-folder  7-11)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – von Bertalanffy, Ludwig, 1962 (Box-folder  7-12)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Panel discussion, 1962 (Box-folder  7-13)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Ferry, W. H., 1963 (Box-folder  7-14)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Leary, Timothy, 1963 (Box-folder  7-15)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Reis, Louis A., 1963 (Box-folder  7-16)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Rudolph, Frederick, 1963 (Box-folder  7-17)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Temko, Allan, 1964 (Box-folder  7-18)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Watts, Alan, 1964 (Box-folder  7-19)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Wieman, Henry, 1964 (Box-folder  7-20)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Harbrecht, Paul, 1965 (Box-folder  7-21)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Hilton, Alice Mary, 1965 (Box-folder  7-22)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Soleri, Paolo, 1965 (Box-folder  7-23)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Theobald, Robert, 1965 (Box-folder  7-24)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Algren, Nelson, 1966 (Box-folder  8-1)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Kaplan, Max, 1966 (Box-folder  8-2)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Medd, Margaret, 1966 (Box-folder  8-3)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Wolfenstein, Martha, 1966 (Box-folder  8-4)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Carmichael, Stokely, 1967 (Box-folder  8-5)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Duncan, Robert, 1967 (Box-folder  8-6)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Dyckman, John, 1967 (Box-folder  8-7)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Goodlett, Carlton B., 1967 (Box-folder  8-8)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Hook, Sidney, 1967 (Box-folder  8-9)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Mezey, Robert, 1967 (Box-folder  8-10)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – O’Brien, Conor Cruise, 1967 (Box-folder  8-11)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Sontag, Susan, 1967 (Box-folder  8-12)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Panel discussion, 1967 (Box-folder  8-13)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Duncan, Robert, 1968 (Box-folder  8-14)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Harris, Marvin, 1968 (Box-folder  8-15)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Lenneberg, Eric H., 1968 (Box-folder  8-16)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Reiser, Oliver L., 1968 (Box-folder  8-17)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Weaver, Pat, 1968 (Box-folder  8-18)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Brown, Claude, 1969 (Box-folder  8-19)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Creeley, Robert, 1969 (Box-folder  8-20)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Ferry, W. H., 1969 (Box-folder  8-21)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – Kiley, Dan, 1969 (Box-folder  8-22)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers – O’Brien, Thomas L., 1969 (Box-folder  8-23)
- Symposium on American Values – Speakers, 1970 (Box-folder  8-24)
- Symposium on American Values – Photographs, 1960s (Box-folder  8-25)
- Visitations (Box-folder  8-26)
- Visiting professors – General - Ephemera (Box-folder  8-27)